All right. In the last video, I said
that um one of the fairly common, if
there's fairly common problems that you
have, someone probably wrote a library
or a package to help with that. And um
one of the fairly common problems you'll
run into is you might want data to stick
around on your page when it reloads. To
demonstrate how this can be a problem,
I've got this variable here called I,
and I'm incrementing it when the page
loads. And so if the page loads, I'm
going to display one. What I would like
is I'd actually like this to show the
number of times I've visited the page.
So every time the page reloads, um, I
should get a higher number. So if I
reload the page, oh, I'm back at one.
And if I reload the page, I'm back at
one. And why is that? Well, because
right here, I'm always telling it to
start at one. Um, so and when I reload
the page, this variable gets reset. It's
a global variable, but it gets reset.
Um, and it'd be nice if we could get our
information to stick around. Well, there
are two ways to do that. There's local
storage and there's session storage. Um,
and you can actually see those if you
come into the inspect tool and you go to
application and then you go into local
storage and you click on whatever page
you're on. In this case, I'm on
http127.0.0.1.
In other words, I'm using live server.
You can see that it stores it as keys
and values.
So this works exactly like you would
expect a dictionary to work where you
have a key and you can look up its
value. Here you can use local storage
and look up its key and its value. And
the same is true for session storage. In
fact you can see live server is actually
storing information here. It's storing
the key of is this first time_log
from liveerver and the value is true.
And in the next video, I'll show you how
to access these. Right now, I'm going to
tell you there is one caveat. Local
storage and session storage always store
things as strings. So, if you want to
access them in any other way, you have
to work around that little um that
little rule. And we'll talk about that
in the next